LAUREN POWERS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

New York, NY |

<u>lauren.powers20@gmail.com</u> |

<u>in LinkedIn/Lauren Powers</u> | GitHub/Lauren Powers I Portfolio/Lauren Powers

I am a Software Engineer with a passion for creating and building. My 12 years of experience in financial operations has helped me turn problem solving and crisis management into an everyday practice. My collaborative and determined approach enables me to see challenges as opportunities to learn and grow.

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Git | GitHub | API | React.js | Python | Django | Node.js | MongoDB | Mongoose | Express | Python | SQL Postgres | Flask

PROJECTS

- Game of Trivia GibHub/Live Site Front end multiple choice game of trivia written in HTML, CSS, and
- Simpsons Quote Generator Github/Live Site A Simpsons quote generator to make you feel nostalgic. Built with React.js.
- B-Side Music GitHub/Live Site Fullstack and CRUD functional database of musicians and artists built with Mongoose, Express, React, and Node. This is a collaborative project completed in a team of five.

EXPERIENCE

New York, NY General Assembly

Software Engineering Fellow

Sept 2022- Dec 2022

- Built fully responsive front end web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and third party API-integrations.
- Developed full stack applications and designed REST APIs with full CRUD functionality using React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, SQL, PeeWee, Flask, and Django.

JP Morgan Chase Bank, N.A.

New York, NY

Assistant Branch Manager- Operations Lead Associate Operations Personal Banker

September 2021- March 2022 June 2018 - September 2021 August 2010 - June 2018

- Manage, trained, and mentored 15+ employees on standard operating procedures, which lead to high annual branch review scores.
- Scored 97%+ on three annual branch audits resulting in increased branch peer ranking.
- Lead and developed branch staff to meet customer's service needs resulting in increased overall satisfaction survey scores.
- Provided leadership, feedback, and coaching on employees performance resulting in high annual branch review scores by 10%-15%.
- Collaborated with Branch Manager to direct sales and all aspects of branch operation, including loss control, compliance, customer retention, and audit standards.
- Educated clients to increase the usage of technology self-service options such as Chase Mobile App, Chase.com, and ATMs exceeding branch score-card metrics.

EDUCATION

General Assembly New York, NY - Software Engineering Immersive Certificate | 2022 State University of New York - College at Purchase - Purchase, NY - Bachelor of the Arts - Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal Studies - The Arts